In this video, we want to look at the final aspect
في هذا الفيديو، نريد أن ننظر إلى الجانب النهائي
used to describe quantitative variables, Outliers.
المستخدم في وصف المتغيرات الكمية، القيم الشاذة.
Outliers are data points that fall very far from the rest of the values in our data set.
القيم الشاذة هي نقاط بيانات تقع بعيدًا جدًا عن باقي القيم في مجموعة البيانات.
In order to determine what is very far,
لتحديد النقاط البعيدة جداً،
there are a number of different methods.
هناك عدة طرق مختلفة.
My usual method for detecting outliers isn't very scientific.
وطريقتي المعتادة لاكتشاف القيم الشاذة ليس علمية جدًا.
Usually, I just look at a histogram and see if
عادة، أكتفي بالنظر إلى المدرج التكراري ورؤية ما إذا
the point is really far from any of the other data points.
كانت النقطة بعيدة عن أي من نقاط البيانات الأخرى.
Again, a quick plot of your data can
مرة أخرى، يساعدك إنشاء مخطط سريع لبياناتك
often help you understand a lot in a short amount of time.
على فهم الكثير في فترة زمنية قصيرة.
In order to illustrate the impact that outliers can
لتوضيح التأثير الذي يمكن أن تحدثه القيم الشاذة
have on the way we report summary statistics,
على الطريقة التي نبلغ بها عن إحصائيات موجزة،
let's consider the salaries of entrepreneurs.
دعونا نفكر في رواتب رواد الأعمال.
Imagine I select ten entrepreneur earnings and I
تخيل أنني اخترت عشرة قيم تمثل عشرة من رواد الأعمال
pull these nine values here as earnings in thousands of dollars,
وسحبت هذه القيم التسع هنا كأرباح بآلاف الدولارات،
and the tenth is the CEO of Facebook.
والعاشر هو الرئيس التنفيذي لـ Facebook.
According to a post by CNN in 2016,
وفقا لما نشرته سي إن إن في عام 2016،
he earned 4.4 million dollars per day.
يحصل على أرباح تقدر بـ 4.4 مليون دولار يوميًا.
Here, we can calculate the mean of these salaries for
هنا، يمكننا حساب متوسط​هذه الأرباح
entrepreneurs based on this data to be approximately 160 million dollars.
لرواد الأعمال بناء على هذه البيانات لتكون حوالي 160 مليون دولار.
This is incredibly misleading.
هذا مضلل بشكل لا يصدق.
Literally zero of the entrepreneurs earned this salary.
وحرفيًا لا يوجد رجل أعمال يحصل على هذا الراتب.
None of the ten salaries are even close to this amount.
ولا يوجد ضمن الرواتب العشرة من يقرب من هذا المبلغ.
A better measure of center would certainly be the median.
أفضل قياس للمركز سيكون بالتأكيد الوسيط.
The median here is calculated at 62,000 dollars a year and is
يتم حساب الوسيط هنا بنحو 62000 دولار سنويًا، وهو
a better indication of what an entrepreneur is likely to earn based on our data.
أفضل مؤشر على الأرباح التي من المرجح أن يكسبها رائد الأعمال بناءً على بياناتنا.
Our standard deviation is also not a great measure in this case.
إن الانحراف المعياري ليس إجراءً كبيرًا في هذه الحالة.
At approximately 482 million dollars,
حوالي 482 مليون دولار،
all this suggests is that our earnings for entrepreneurs are really spread out,
كل هذا يشير إلى أن أرباح رواد الأعمال تنتشر بالفعل،
but that really isn't fair either.
ولكن هذا ليس صحيحًا أيضًا.
Just one point is really far from the rest.
مجرد نقطة واحدة بعيدة عن باقي النقاط.
Like really really far.
فمثل هذا بعيد جداً حقيقةً.